Guide to the Owen Wister Literary Society (OWLS) Undergraduate and Alumnae Records, 1927-2010 UA 059
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Owen Wister Literary Society (OWLS) Undergraduate and Alumnae records
1927-2010
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University. Owen Wister Literary Society
UA 059
10.5 Linear Feet (4 boxes and 5 scrapbook boxes)
The collection consists of scrapbooks, minute books, financial records, and other materials relating to the founding and operation of both the Owen Wister Literary Society (OWLS) undergraduate group and the alumnae group, 1927-2002. OWLS was founded in 1924.
Biographical / Historical
The Owen Wister Literary Society (OWLS) was founded by Adele Roensch in 1924. It was named after Owen Wister, an American writer famous for his novel The Virginian. The purpose of the organization was to further cultural and social interests on the Rice campus and to promote friendship, understanding, and fellowship among its members. Since 1924 a parallel society, consisting of OWLS alumnae, had been founded and its records are also included.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of scrapbooks, minute books, financial records, and other materials relating to the founding and operation of both the OWLS undergraduate group and the OWLS alumnae group.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Acquistion Information
Gifts of various donors and past OWLS members, 1985-2004.
General
Portions of this collection are available online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/61405.
Index Terms
Subjects
Women; Literature -- Societies, etc.; Literature and society -- United States; Universities and colleges; Social life and customs
Document Types
financial records; scrapbooks; constitutions; directories; corrrespondence
- Series I: OWLS administrative files, 1927-2002, 111822
  - History, 115036 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitutions, 115037 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership lists, 1962-1972, 115038 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - OWLS song book, 115039 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1940s-1973, 115040 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1980s, 115041 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dues Paid ledgers:1964/75, 1983/84, 115042 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Financial ledgers: 1963-64, 1965-66, 1967-68, 115043 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Financial Reports: 1962-63, 1963-64, 1964-65, 115044 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Financial Reports: 1992-95, 1997-98, 2002, 115045 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - News clippings, 1927-92, n.d., current, 115046 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Scripts for 2 skits, n.d., 115047 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lit Luncheon, 1990-1996, 115048 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photos, 115050 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Party invitations, 115051 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Meeting notices, 115052 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Questionnaires, 115053 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Welcome letters, 115054 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ephemera, 115055 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - President's notebooks: 1941/42-49/50, 1949/50-65/66, 115056 (Box 2)
  - Minutes books: 1942-58, 1949-64, 1964-77, 1981-89, 1989-94, 1993-98, 115254 (Box 2)
  - Alumnae Directories, 1940s-2000s, 115057 (Box 3)
  - Meeting, minutes, memories notebooks, 261665
    - 1988-89, 1999-2000, 2000-01, 261666 (Box 9)
    - 2001-02, 2002-03, 2003-04, 261667 (Box 9)
    - 2004-05, 2005-06, 2006-07, 261668 (Box 9)
    - 2007-08, 2008-09, 2009-10, 261669 (Box 9)
- Series II: Scrapbooks, 115030
  - 1927-53; 1931-36; 1938; 1941/42-42/43, 115031 (Box 4)
  - 1943-44; 1944-45; 1947-48, 115032 (Box 5)
  - 1946-47; 1953-55, 115033 (Box 6)
  - 1948-49; 1949-50; 1950-52; 1955-56; 1962-63, 115034 (Box 7)
  - 1975-89; 1989, 115035 (Box 8)
- Series III: Alumnae binders, 1998-2007
  - Binder 1998-2003 (Box 9)
  - Binder 2003-2009 (Box 9)